A Guide to the Records of the Office of the President, William E. Lavery, 1975-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Records of the Office of the President, William E. Lavery, 1975-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Lavery, William Edward
RG 2/12
31 Cubic Feet 23 boxes
William Edward Lavery (1930-2009) was president of Virginia Tech from 1975 to 1987. The collection contains mainly incoming and outgoing correspondence (1975-1987) concerning college activities and issues of Lavery's administration including admission and records; commencement exercises; inaugural activities; homecoming; the Alumni Association; faculty and student affairs; speeches and speech material.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Records of the Office of the President, William E. Lavery were transferred to the University Archives in 2011.
Biographical Note
Born in Geneseo, N.Y. on November 20, 1930, to the late John R. and Mary Irene O'Bryan, William Edward Lavery earned his bachelor's degree from Michigan State University, his master's in public administration from George Washington University, and his doctorate in extension administration from the University of Wisconsin.
He began his professional career as a teacher and coach at Clarence Central High School in Clarence, N.Y., before serving two years in the United States Army. He was a veteran of the Korean Conflict. He married the former Peggy Johnson of Pawnee City, Neb., in 1956, and the couple had four children, Debra, Lori, Mary Beth, and K. Michael. He began working for the federal Extension Service's Division of Management Operations in 1956, where he remained until 1966.
Succeeding President Hahn, William E. Lavery became the university's president on January 1, 1975. Lavery had been executive vice president since 1973, preceded by five years as vice president for finance and two years as director of administration for the Extension division. He first came to the university in 1966. Complementing the years of explosive growth under his predecessor, his presidency not only brought stability to the university but also expanded its growth into different areas. Lavery placed a high priority on alleviating shortages of classroom, laboratory, and office space – increasing the total inventory of available space by 50.1 percent. The new "infill" concept for constructing buildings and additions would subsequently win an award from the American Planning Association. A $108-million construction program included additions to Newman Library and the War Memorial Gymnasium, construction of Johnston Student Center, and a $17.5 million complex to house the Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine, opening to students in 1980.
The president also emphasized research, and expenditures in support of research totaled over $70.2 million by the fiscal year of 1987, moving Virginia Tech into the nation's top fifty research universities. He enhanced research opportunities by establishing the Corporate Research Center. The center received an antenna to link Virginia Tech to the world via satellite, and the Extension division developed a series of twenty-six downlink sites throughout the state. Installation began on a new communication system for the campus, the university purchased a supercomputer, and the first proposal was developed for what later became the Blacksburg Electronic Village. Additionally, Virginia Tech played a vital role in developing the concept for Virginia's Center for Innovative Technology.
Under his watch, the university introduced a core curriculum and added degree programs. The number of minority scholarships and fellowships grew, and students applied in record numbers. Faculty salaries moved from the bottom third to the top fourth among research universities. The university opened the Cranwell International Center. Lavery hired the university's first vice president for development, Charles Forbes, who launched a campaign to raise $50 million and then raised more than $108 million. Lavery also hired the university's first woman vice president, Sandra Sullivan, vice president for student affairs.
In other developments, President Ronald Reagan appointed Lavery chair of the USAID Board for International Food and Agricultural Development, and the U. S. Secretary of the Treasury appointed him to the National Savings Bond Committee, where he chaired the Higher Education Industry Campaign. He also served on the first NCAA Presidential Commission. In 1985, Xavier University in the Philippines presented him with an honorary doctorate. During his presidency, the National Conference of Christians and Jews presented him with the Brotherhood Award and the governor of Virginia appointed him to serve on the Commission on Virginia's Transportation in the 21st Century.
A controversial land swap in 1986 – in which Virginia Tech traded 247 acres of land for 1,700 acres needed for agricultural research – along with highly publicized problems with the basketball program posed challenges to Lavery's presidency. Despite the fact he developed a reorganization plan for the Athletic Association, negative publicity continued. On October 16, 1987 Lavery announced his resignation, effective December 31, 1987. He continued to serve the university, first as honorary chancellor, then, after October 1, 1988, as the William B. Preston Professor of International Affairs, and, after his retirement on August 1, 1991, as president emeritus.
The university recognized his contributions by honoring him with the Ruffner Medal in 1993 and by dedicating the William E. Lavery Animal Health Research Center in his honor in 1995. Additionally, the Class of 1997 named its class ring in his honor. He died on February 16, 2009.
Source: Buchanan, Todd, Lawrence G. Hincker, and Clara B. Cox. Images & Reflections: Virginia Tech, 1872-1997. Blacksburg, Va: Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1997.
Scope and Content
This collection contains mainly incoming and outgoing correspondence (1975-1987) concerning college activities and issues of Lavery's administration including admission and records; commencement exercises; inaugural activities; homecoming; the Alumni Association; faculty and student affairs; speeches and speech material. The collection also contains correspondence from alumni expressing their perspectives on the negative publicity surrounding the Athletic Association and Virginia Tech Basketball.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically. For the most part, the original order is retained.
Index Terms
Persons:
Lavery, William Edward
Subjects:
University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Series I: 1974-1975
  - Annual Report, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blacksburg, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Business, College of, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Business Manager, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Business Week, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Catalog Committee, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cincinnati, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7a)
  - Civil Rights (3 folders), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
  - Commandant of Cadets, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Commencement Committee, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Commencement Exercises (2 folders), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Committee on Patents, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Commission, Committee Membership Listed, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Computing Center, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Context - VPI & SU Quarterly Magazine, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cooperative Program, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Corp of Cadets, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Council of Presidents, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dairy Science, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Development - Mountain Lake and Horton Property, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Economics Department, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Education, College of (2 folders), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - Energy Conservation - VPI & SU ranked first among state colleges, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Engineering, College of, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Engineering Science and Mechanics, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Equatic Ecology, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Extension - General, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Faculty Senate, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Football, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Founder's Day, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Freshman Reception, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Governor's Day, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Hahn, T. Marshall Jr., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - History Department, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Horticulture, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Inauguration Committee, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Inauguration Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Inauguration - Local Arrangements (2 folders), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
  - Inauguration - President Lavery (5 folders), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 44-46, Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Inauguration Print (2 folders), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Information Services, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Innovative Instruction, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Invitations - Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - U.S Army Commissioning Ceremony
    - Florida Citrus Sports
    - Administration Retreat at Camp Fincastle
    - Sigma Chi Derby Day
    - Conference for Career Counseling and Vocational Education
    - The Commonwealth Prayer Breakfast
  - Judicial Committee, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lavery - Personal (3 folders), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
    - Correspondence on presidential appointment
  - Library, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Radiation Safety Committee, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Student Budget Board - Commission on Student Affairs, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - University Calendar, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - University Development - Bell, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - William H. Ruffner Medal
  - Virginia Tech Amateur Radio Association, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - VPI & SU Cable Interconnect with Blacksburg TV Cable System, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - VP of Academic Affairs Search, 1975
    - Letters, Lists, and Schedules, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Women's Organizations nominations requests VPAA, 1975-01-13 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - University Presidents Nominations requests VPAA 1, 1975-01 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - University Presidents Nominations requests VPAA 2, 1975-01 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Advertisement VPAA, 1975-01 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Qualification Statement VPAA (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Mission of University VPAA (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Requests for Student Nominations, 1975-01 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Minority Nominations, 1975-01-13 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Selection Procedure VPAA, 1975-01-06, 1975-01-10 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Faculty, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Series II: 1976
  - Acting Vice President for Special Projects, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - IBM Executive Information Systems Seminar
    - Overhead allocation procedures
    - Advance study policy - staff agenda
    - Affirmative action plan for the handicapped
  - Alumni Association, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Alumni Association, President of, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Civil Rights, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - University's Affirmative Action Plan
  - Commencement Exercises, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Dreiling, Professor Fred R., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Dedications, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Carol B. Rector Tennis Pavilion Dedication, 1976
    - William H. Sardo, Jr. Pallet and Container Research Laboratory
  - Extension - General, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Football, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Founders Day, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Home Economics, College of, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Homecoming, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Human Nutrition and Foods, Department of, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Institutional Research, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - International Development, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Judicial Committee, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Learning Resources Center, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Political Science, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Research Division, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - State Council on Higher Education, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Speeches (2 folders), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
    - Kiwanis Club of Richmond, 1976
    - Dark-Fire Cured Tobacco Recognition Banquet, 1976
    - Veterinary Medical Association
    - American Institute of Cooperation (AIC) National Institute on Cooperative Education
    - International Development Conference
    - "Future of Agriculture in Virginia"
    - "Tomorrow's Challenges for Extension"
    - 80th Annual Meeting and Trade Show - Virginia State Horticultural Society
    - Virginia Agribusiness Council
  - The Lane Company, Inc., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Vice President for Academic Affairs, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Vice President for Administration, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Vice President for Student Affairs, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Virginia Academy of Science, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Virginia Department of Agriculture and Commerce, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Tidewater Consortium, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Truck and Ornamentals Research Station, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Visiting Scholar Program, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series III: 1977
  - Automated Data Processing (ADP) Policy Committee, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Aerospace and Ocean Engineering, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Agriculture and Life Sciences, College of, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Association, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Animal Industry Day, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Basketball, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Commencement Exercises, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Consulting, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Consulting activities of faculty, 1976
    - University consulting policy, 1977
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Council of Presidents, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Counseling Center, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Dairy Science Department, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Dedications of Buildings, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Development - Bell, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Development - General, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Donaldson Brown Center, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical Authority, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Economics, Department of, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Education, College of, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Engineering and Buildings Division, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Executive Bulletins, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Extension - Dean, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Extension - General (2 folders), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Founders Day, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Governor's Day, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Governor of Virginia, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Highway Department, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Homecoming, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Honor System, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Institutional Research, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Information Services, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Lavery - Personal, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence
  - Legislators - General Assembly (2 folders), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 40-41)
  - Legislators - US Congress, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Library Archival Donation, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - New River Valley Association for Retarded Citizens, Inc., 1977 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "Opportunities for Superior Students", 1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Performing Arts and Communications, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Pratt Bequest, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Sociology Department, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Southern Piedmonst Research and Continuing Education Center, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Speeches (2 folders), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - "Strategies in Land and Water Use to Meet Noncommodity Needs", 1977
    - "Service and Education" speech at the District Rotary Conference, 1977
    - "Extension and the Land-Grant University", 1977
    - Lavery's Address to the Soil Conservation Society of America, 1977
    - "Land Resource Management" by George Bagley, President of the National Association of Conservation Districts
  - Sporn Award, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - State Council of Higher Education, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Statistics Department, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Student Affairs - Payne, A.C., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Student Budget Board, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Student Government Association, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Student Housing, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Student Letters, to and from, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Student Organizations, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Student Union, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Vice President for Administration, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Vice President for Development, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Academy of Science, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Colleges, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Truck and Ornamentals Research Station, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Water Resources Center, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Western Region Consortium, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Series IV: 1978
  - Accounting Department, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 22A)
  - American Overseas Placement Project, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Board of Visitors, Report to, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Budget Matters, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Central Virginia Consortium, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Chemical Engineering Department, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Chemistry Department, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Cincinnati Award, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Citadel National Student Conference, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Civil Rights, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Commandant of Cadets, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Commencement Exercises (2 folders), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
  - Commission on Faculty Affairs, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Commission on Student Affairs (3 folders), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 36-38)
  - Computer Center, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Computer Science Department, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Consortium for Continuing Higher Education in Northern Virginia (3 folders), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 41, Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Cooperative Education Program, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Corp of Cadets (2 folders), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - Council of Presidents, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Counseling Center, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Engineering Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - English Department, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Entomology Department, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Enrollment Statistics, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Environmental Studies, Center for, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Extension Dean (2 folders), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Extension - General (4 folders), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15-18)
  - Extension/State Technical Services, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Exxon Education Foundation, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Reception (2 folders), Oct. 3, 4, 5, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
  - Faculty Senate (4 folders), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 23-26)
  - Food Science and Technology, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Football, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Founders Day, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Fulbright-Hays Award, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Hahn, T. Marshall Jr., 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lavery Personal, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Marine Science Education (2 folders), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Miscellaneous (2 folders), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Montgomery County School System
    - Leafy- Vegetable Washer System
    - Montgomery County Emergency Assistance
    - Thirteenth Annual Seminar on the Federal Home Loan Bank System
  - Naming Buildings, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - National Science Foundation, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - National Wooden Pallet and Container Association, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Occupational Health and Safety, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Office of Federal Programs - American Association of State Colleges and Universities, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 11A)
  - Organizational Charts, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Performing Arts, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Philippines, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Physics, Department of, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Placement Services, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Placement Services - Annual Report, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Placement Services - General, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Policy Changes, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Poultry Science, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Provost, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Public Administration and Policy, Center for (2 folders), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
  - R - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - C. Eugene Rowe
    - Charles W. Rector
  - Registrar, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Research Division, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - ROTC (2 folders), 1978 (Box 6, Folder 27-28)
  - Scholarships and Grants, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Sea Grant, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Security, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Speeches (2 folders), 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
  - Speech Material, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Staff Meetings, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - State Council on Higher Education (3 folders), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
  - Statistics Department, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Talent Search, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Tenure, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - University Council (2 folders), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - University Distinguished Professor, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - University Services and Auxiliary Enterprises (3 folders), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 13-15)
  - V - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Military Institute
    - Virginia Commonwealth University
    - Virginia Center on Aging
    - Representatives for the Valley of Virginia Consortium's Articulation Committee
  - Vice President for Development and University Relations, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 16A)
  - Virginia Academy of Science, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Coal Research and Development Advisory Committee, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Community College System, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Department of Agriculture and Commerce (3 folders), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 20-22)
  - Virginia Tech Magazine, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - VPI Educational Foundation - President's Fund, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - William H. Ruffner Medal, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Series V: 1979
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Publications (2 folders), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Admissions and Records, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Automated Data Processing (ADP) Policy Committee, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Economics Department, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Agriculture and Life Sciences, College of (2 folders), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Agriculture and Urban Studies, College of, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Aircraft, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Association, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - American Council on Higher Education, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Anaerobe Laboratory, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Arts and Sciences, College of, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Basketball, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Chesapeake Bay Legislative Advisory Committee, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Coal and Energy Research Center (3 folders), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 17-19)
  - Commencement, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Committees - Miscellaneous, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - University Council and Faculty Senate
    - Building Committee
    - Employee Benefits Committee
    - Honor System Review Board
    - Judicial Committee
    - Scholarship and Student Aid